sciencenewsjournal.com 2019-05-06

# Privacy Policy - Science News Journal

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (Personal Information) or allows us to contact you. Generally this information is requested when you are asked to comment on the article, entering a contest, or ordering e-mail newsletters.

If you choose not to provide personal information, you can still use most of the features on the website, but you will not be able to comment and subscribe daily newsletter or areas that require your personal details.

## How is information collected?

From cookies – like many websites, we use “cookies.” We use persistent, identifying cookies to detect your browser, remember your information and to link your activities to you. While you can take steps to warn off, block or disable cookies, if you do, the site may not function and appear as we have designed it. For more information about cookies, including controlling and deleting them, please visit the www.aboutcookies.org website.

From traffic references – when you visit a website, you unveil certain information about you, such as your IP address, time of visit, place from which you accessed our website. ScienceNewsJournal.com, like other operators, stores this information.

From social networks – while entering a contest, or ordering e-mail newsletters, we may ask to share website content on your social networks like Facebook, Twitter, … So you should review your privacy settings on your social network accounts because those settings determine and govern what information may be made available to us.

## Log files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on ScienceNewsJournal.com to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

## Security

ScienceNewsJournal.com strictly protects the security of your personal information and honours your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

## Distribution

ScienceNewsJournal.com does not distribute personal information to any third parties without your prior express consent. Please be aware that it may be possible, depending on your use of various features on website, that some of your personal information is available on publically accessible web page(s). One example would be commenting the posts.

## Changes to this document

Changes to this document may be made any time without warning. ScienceNewsJournal.com may or may not notify you of changes in this policy, however, we will make an effort to notify you if there are any major changes to this policy. You will not be notified about changes related to clarification and/or elaboration of parts of this policy.

For any suggestions and comments regarding ScienceNewsJournal.com or our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at **info  (at) ScienceNewsJournal (dot) com**
